Planet of the Humans is a documentary film directed by Jeff Gibbs.
Forget all you have heard about how “Renewable Energy” is our salvation.
It is all a myth that is very lucrative for some.
Feel-good stuff like electric cars, etc.
Such vehicles are actually powered by coal, natural
gas… or dead salmon in the Northwest.
Self - Narrator (voice), played by Jeff Gibbs.
Self (archive footage), played by Chris Dodd.
Planet of the Humans is a 2019 American environmental documentary
film written, directed, and produced by Jeff Gibbs.
The film was executively produced by Michael Moore.
Moore released it on YouTube for free viewing on April 21, 2020, the
eve of the 50th anniversary of the first Earth Day.
The film examines mainstream environmental groups' partnerships with billionaires,
corporations, and wealthy family foundations in the fight to save the planet.
The film questions whether green energy can solve society's expanding resource depletion without reducing consumption and/or
population growth, as all existing forms of energy generation require some kind of consumption of finite resources.
Essentially the film questions whether renewable energy sources such as biomass energy, wind
power, and solar energy are as clean and renewable as they are portrayed to be.
Upon its release, Planet of the Humans generated intense
controversy and critical reception was mixed.
It was criticized by some climate scientists, environmentalists and renewable energy proponents as
misleading and outdated, but received praise for its contrarian stance and for provoking discussion.
The filmmakers have defended the film from criticism.
On May 25, 2020, Planet of the Humans was removed from YouTube in response to a claim
of copyright infringement, which PEN America condemned as censorship.
The filmmakers challenged the claim, arguing that the fragment was
used under fair use and that free speech was subverted.
Twelve days later, YouTube allowed the film to be viewed again.
In November 2020, Moore removed it from YouTube where it was available for free and made it available on
Amazon, Apple and Google's rental channels, although a copy remains on the Internet Archive.
As of 2023, the documentary is available on Michael
Moore's official YouTube channel.
The film explores themes of capitalism, energy policy,
fossil fuel, billionaire, corporate greed.
The tone is uplifting.